Welcome into another free agency
Friday's here in the Big Bear AI Command
Center studio. I'm your host Brian
Cooker Jr. And I don't even need to
introduce this cat next to me. We didn't
sat down so many times now. Jeremy
McNichols is in the building after
signing a new deal with the Washington
Commanders. Man, congratulations.
Appreciate you. Yeah, man. How big is
this moment for you, man? You signed
another contract, man. Especially as a
running back, nothing's promised, man,
and you keep it going, bro. It's huge,
bro. It's huge. Like I was just taking
this off season and like kind of just
catch up on all of my career and just
life, you know? I was just like, you
know, every season go by so fast. You
just but the off season I usually take
and be like just deep breath and be
like, all right.
Well, this big this one big, man, 10.
So, I'm going into 10 and then like you
said, just
the longevity and the work that has been
put in since I Pop Warner, you know, and
throughout the league and just year
after year grinding. Um this one feels
different, though. It just it just has a
different feel to it.
And you like you said, yeah, just
running backs don't last too long.
Right.
So, being able to pass that threshold is
just it's a little different feeling,
for sure. Is it just the time frame that
makes it feel different? What makes the
all of this feel so different for you?
10. It just Yeah, it just the double
digit. It just, you know, I was you
know, 2 years ago I was like, I'm almost
at 10.
You know, okay, keep scratching and I
like last year I was like, this nine.
Okay, you just feel I'm like, now you
going into 10. So, that's that's what
the the goal was always 10. You know,
the goal was like, you get to 10 it's
just different, you know?
So, when you reflect this off season,
knowing you're going into 10, knowing
that you're going to make it to this
goal, man, what stood out to you when
you did this reflection? Shh. Just just
the grind from when I was a kid. Just
that dream. Just like
just seeing how like, you know, going
back to that age of what is probably
eight or nine years old and having that
dream of playing in the league.
You don't I'm telling you right now, I
wasn't dreaming of 10. I was just
dreaming of getting in the door. You
know what I'm saying? So,
that's what that's what I was like just
reminiscing about, you know? And then
finally getting there, you just like,
damn. Okay.
You kind of start looking back, you
know? And then come back forward
with gratitude. Be like,
I'm just going to go harder, you know?
Wow, just going harder. It's crazy to
think I'm just going to go harder in
[laughter] year 10, man. What makes you
say you want to do year 10 and run it
back with the burgundy and gold?
First of all, I feel good. My body feels
good. My mind feels good.
Just that flow state with football and
just, you know, life.
And then just coming back to
a place that believed in me, you know?
Where I was I was I mean, I was coming
off of not playing on practice squad,
you know, off of injury. And
it was almost over, you know? And AP
came over here, DQ came over here, AP
Coach Lynn and
they gave me opportunity. So, if they
you know, they believe in me, so I
continue to be believe in them. And when
they was like they gave me a call, it
was like, we want you back. I mean, it
was a no-brainer.
You know?
>> You said it was almost over. When that
reality sets in that, hey man, this
might be it for me, especially when it's
not necessarily your choice, right? Like
that don't sound like that was your
choice. Clearly, you still had a lot
more left in the tank.
How hard is that to get through when you
feel like you're you're losing control
of what you have control over, which is
your career, man? How tough was that
part of your career? Tough. It was
I still remember I still, you know, when
I those days where I don't I don't want
to get up and go to practice. It's too
hot.
I remember sitting on that couch hurt
and watching other guys play back in
2022. I tore my labrum in in uh
in camp. Tore my labrum in camp, went
back home for the first time, my first
year never playing football.
And I was just like,
this are you okay with this being over,
you know? And I wasn't. I wasn't okay
with it, you know? As I was on the couch
I was, you know,
I was at home for the first time.
And, you know, going through the
recovery process.
Usually you see the you know, you see
the guys in the locker room and you No,
it wasn't nobody there. It was quiet. It
was just quiet. Me versus me,
you [clears throat] know? For 7 months
of recovery.
And then you know, going into 2023,
it was
man, do I want to play?
Do you know? Just going back and forth.
Am I am I good enough? You know, can I
bounce back from this injury?
And then I was just like, you know, I
got a good team around me and it's like
just
jump in and go. Go for it. Like, you
know what I'm saying? You have nothing
to lose. And then
you know, getting to this point, you
know, of signing today, going into, you
know, another season.
That's why it means so much to me.
Yeah. Do you think you'll ever shake
that feeling, though, right? Because
that is a lot right there where you're
like,
do I have a spot in this league? Am I
going to continue to play, man? Am I
going to get those minutes? Do you still
carry that with you today? Because at
this point, the Commanders have invested
multiple contracts into you now, but do
you still feel that like extra chip on
your shoulder from having those moments,
those down moments?
>> No doubt. No doubt. Cuz I like I always
I always go back to those moments.
I don't want to get up at 5:00 in the
morning, 6:00 in the morning work out.
Hey, bro, when you was on that couch,
you wish you could have signed that
contract.
Yeah.
>> Like you wish you could be on that
field. So, don't take no moment for
granted.
And that's just how I go out there and
play and practice every single day and
come to work, you know?
And um
that's why like, you know what I'm
saying? This just it mean it means more
it's more than football, you know? It's
it's just it's a lifestyle.
It's it's just a sense of gratitude and
thankfulness and that's why I like to
show when I go on the field, you know,
that you can get through anything, you
know? And
those opportunities
don't come you know, come around a lot
of the time.
You know?
And uh
show, you know, put light on that and
and share your story when those those
dark days, you could get those It's
going to be It's light at the every you
know, in the tunnel.
So, you know, every time I come to work
or go on the field, like that's what I
want to continuously show to the world.
And we appreciate you sharing these
stories because it shows in the field,
right? Like all of a sudden, you get a
carry 60 yards, you break it out. Like
we've seen that multiple times where
soon as your number's called, even if it
hasn't been called all game, you're
ready for that, man. And last year you
got to be part of a top 10 rushing
offense pretty much the whole season
long. And you mentioned Anthony Lynn,
he's decided to come back as well and be
a part of this offense, man. How has he
been able to impact your career?
It's I want to say him more
off the field than on the field, you
know? We go back when I was on practice
squad in San Francisco, you know, and he
was the assistant running back coach,
assistant head coach.
He was kind of in the background, you
know? And he was he always check on me
like, how's your mental? I know you want
to be playing. I know you played in this
league, you're in year seven and you
haven't touched the field. How you
doing, you know? And I was like,
that type of stuff mean way more to me
than than than coaching, you know? You
get to this level everybody good at
football, you know? But it's like those
little things that help you like, you
know, just doing like, you know, the
mental stuff off the field and we do it
in our and you know, we do some of this
stuff in our um
in our room. And that's what he's big
on. He's like, everybody in this room
can play football. And I'm going to have
you guys ready for Sunday. But how can I
get you guys that extra mental inch when
it comes to like late in the game or,
you know, how can I get you guys in that
flow state when it's crazy. It might be
a minute left and we down seven and it's
chaos going on. Like I want you guys to
be able to hear nothing, you know? It's
like that Beats commercial when you put
them on and noise canceling, you know?
And
so, he's he's meant a lot and that's the
reason that's another reason why I came
back and want to continuously come back
is is is cuz of him. And, you know, he
trusted me. He trusted me not even, you
know, seeing me on the field, you know?
Just as a person and
and then also when he did put me on the
field, obviously I wanted to make him
look right, you know? I want to make
sure he's right, you know? It means it
means a lot to me that you trust me,
okay, I'm going to trust you and I'm
going to go do my job at a high level
for you. And that leadership is so
valuable, especially look at that
running back room. There's so many young
guys now, it looks a lot different,
right? You and Bill are so far the only
carryovers. Now we have a Rashad White,
we have a Jerome Ford, like younger guys
in there. How does Jeremy McNichols fit
in this running back room and how can
you make your impact felt? I'm going to
get in where I fit in, you know? I don't
really
I you know, I look I don't look at
myself as a running back. I look at
myself as a football just a football
player, you know? And that just means
doing whatever wherever help is needed
on our team, you know, on or off the
field, that's where I fit in, you know?
If the guys need help or if it's like,
hey Jeremy, you probably only play five
snaps this game, but these but you need
to help these guys on the sideline. All
right, cool. It's if that's going to
help us win, you know what I'm saying?
Like or if it's like, hey, you got to
step up and, you know, start or
whatever, play third, whatever the case
may be, play teams.
It's wherever wherever fit, you know?
I'm just blessed to have a helmet on
Sunday and be able to go play for my,
you know, for my teammates and for this
city. You know, it's just
go out there with with joy, you know?
And just be light.
That's where I'm going to fit in in the
room. For 10 years, man. That is a
beautiful thing and what a blessing. And
you said it, my goal was to hit that
10-year mark. Well, brother, you
achieved it. You're here now, man. So,
what's the next goal for Jeremy
McNichols?
Man, chase a Super Bowl. Oh, yeah. Yeah,
chase a Super Bowl, for sure. But more
so
just
be
be the person in the room and in the
building that, you know, people going to
remember and be like, he taught me
something, you know, or
you know, like with with Bill, like
teaching Bill or mentoring and helping
mentor and Bill, like Bill, this is how
you, you know, you want to take care of
your body or this is how you want to
watch film or
put some more time here, you know, just
like little stuff that's going to make
some of the players better, you know.
Just [snorts] being able to be a, you
know, a testimony to share my story with
other players and help them be better.
Mhm. And even if it all stopped now,
bro, I think you have accomplished that,
man. I think you have made your impact
felt, man. I love when we do this and in
the background there's family and it
shows like the love that you have, man,
cuz you could be in here all by
yourself, for sure, but it's your
family, it's the loved ones that are
here for you that I hope remind you of
everything you have accomplished and
done, man. So, we appreciate you, Jeremy
McNichols. We appreciate you, bro. You
always show love when you're in this
building, man, and we are so happy to
have you back in the burgundy and gold.
Appreciate you. Commander's family, this
is crazy Friday with our guy, Jeremy
McNichols, running it back one more time
in the burgundy and gold. We appreciate
you, bro. Thank you, bro.